Joshua Lee

San Diego, CA

760-687-5780 <u>jp@joshlee.cc</u>

PROFILE

Skilled data analyst with six years of experience in building analytics tools that help businesses improve profitability. Business experience in logistics, mobile gaming, and SaaS. Full stack data skillset that includes SQL, Python, DBT, and various business intelligence tools, most notably Sigma and Tableau.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Flock Freight

Senior Data Analyst

San Diego, CA

September 2021 – Present

- Develop, update, and maintain Snowflake SQL queries in DBT to combine data from multiple business systems.
- Build comprehensive reporting dashboards in Sigma and Mode that enables sales leadership to monitor business health and dig into underlying trends. This reporting has helped the carrier team drive a 15x increase in sales margin over the past several years.
- Intake analytics requests from carrier sales, compliance, risk management and pricing teams. Assess viability, define scope, and produce timely solutions that fulfill the needs of the original requests.
- Collaborate with carrier network managers to identify possible opportunities to further develop our strategic carrier base. Perform ad-hoc analyses on carrier network business initiatives to assess overall impact and cost-benefit tradeoffs.
- Assist junior team members with implementation of business requirements, troubleshooting SQL, and dashboard development.

Redemption Games

San Diego, CA

Data Analyst

January 2019 – September 2021

- Built and maintained Tableau dashboards containing key game KPIs such as monetization and user retention.
- Wrote advanced SQL queries to extract data from Google Big Query data warehouse.
- Implemented a scalable daily ETL pipeline on Google Cloud using PySpark and Dataproc.
- Created automated extraction and upload of marketing data from REST API to Google Big Query.
- Worked cross-functionally with engineering and product teams to identify and implement new analytic reporting capabilities.

- Performed deep dives into user data to find valuable insights that improved gameplay experience.
- Analyzed A/B test results and presented findings to product team.
- Monitored new version release KPIs and flagged potential issues impacting player experience.

PTC - Vuforia Services

San Diego, CA

Customer Operations Analyst

September 2016 - January 2019

- Provisioned and managed SDK licenses for proprietary AR software platform.
- Provided Tier 1 support for online portal and SDK cloud API usage.
- Handled monthly billing and payment processing through Zuora.
- Compiled billing and payment collection data and presented bi-weekly updates to management.

SKILLS

Programming: SQL, Python, DBT, Git

Data Warehouse: Snowflake, Google Big Query

Business Intelligence: Tableau, Google Data Studio, Sigma, Mode, Excel

EDUCATION

University of California-Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA

Bachelor of Science in Financial Mathematics/Statistics

June 2016